<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/3.2" created="2015-03-24 18:01" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Faye Cheadle</title>
	<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com</link>
	<description>bim bam!</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 18:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.1</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://www.fayecheadle.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://www.fayecheadle.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>faye</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>amerasu@gmail.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[faye]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Faye]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

	<wp:category><wp:term_id>1</wp:term_id><wp:category_nicename>uncategorized</wp:category_nicename><wp:category_parent></wp:category_parent><wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></wp:cat_name></wp:category>

	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.2</generator>

	<item>
		<title>First Post!</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=1</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 04:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=1</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[So, what's this blog going to be about?  Whatever I want.  Hah!  There is no clear purpose right now other than to be an outlet for my writing.  But I'll start with an introductory post, since those are always fun.  My name is Faye Cheadle and I'm from Burke, Virginia.  Burke is a suburb of Washington, D.C.  It's small enough for people to say "I'm from 30 minutes outside of DC" instead of "I'm from Burke, Virginia".  Even if you <em>do</em> say your from Burke, you usually have to add where it is in relation to DC to prevent awkward looks or expectant silences in the conversation.  Both of my parents are successful immigrants, which has shaped my worldview quite a bit.  I grew up around lush trees and grass and logs that would be pulled up to look for salamanders and worms.  I tried playing with neighborhood kids, but it would never last long before I started crying about something.  I'd usually retreat back to my bedroom to read or sit watching TV and movies or playing computer games.  Solitary activities for a shy girl.  My older brother was a fan of science fiction and fantasy, which ended up rubbing off on me and my little sister.  That didn't really help with the shyness...or acceptance.  Other kids were always confused that I would want to read books that were 1000 pages long and already knew most of the words in the class vocabulary books.  When I did socialize, it was with other nerdy girls.  I resented this for some time, because it always looked like the popular, gregarious girls were so much happier than I was.  However, early in high school, I figured out that their friends didn't really <em>like</em> them.  These were marriages of social convenience and show, without the real support or shared values of true friends.  From then on, I worried much less about how many people liked me and concerned myself with trying to find people that I could be happy around.

Pre-school, elementary school, and high school went by like a blur.  There are defining moments of course, but things didn't get really interesting for me until college.  I was an unsure, wandering spirit before then.  So what happened in college and afterwards?  Did I find myself?  Sort of.  It was a little more bumpy than the movies where someone lands on their true self in an epiphany.  I had to scrounge around a bit.  There were little mini-ephiphanies, I guess, but it was a very halting, jolting process.  There was no one moment where I said "Ah, yes, this is it".  And you usually don't really "find" yourself, like looking for something you know you've lost.  Things get degraded, pressures and expectations are piled on one another.  Then you wake up confused, not completely realizing what's going on but with a feeling that <em>something's </em>gone all crooked.  And then you feel around, pawing at some things, grabbing on to others, until you can pull yourself out into a more well-lit corner of the room.  You remember the things you liked when you were a kid, and decide that these are perfectly fine things to like.  Great things to like, even.  You find new ideas that have somehow always been inside you, but someone else has managed to articulate clearly and coherently.  Sometimes you realize you were wrong, easily letting go of certain ideas, and having difficulty letting go of others.

What did I find?  What did I let go of?  I found philosophy.  I found lifelong friends.  I realized that I didn't really want to be a Computer Scientist (this happened, quite unfortunately, after I already had the degree).  After being told for so long that you have to accept with the flaws of your friends, I found out that you shouldn't have to put up with people that are unhappy and cynical.  Condescension and arrogance don't equal confidence.  Real confidence comes when you no longer need someone else's approval to feel good about yourself.  I realized that I don't believe in God or religion, but I do believe in the importance of a good philosophy.  Inspiring art is also important and can feed your soul more than any dogma.  I believe in an individual's right to their own life, and recognize how important a community of good individuals is.  I'm creative.  I like to make stories and use my imagination.  I revere scientists and their work, but don't have the meticulous nature to do this kind of work myself.  You have to define yourself by what you value and love, not by the things that you revile.  I've realized these things and many more, all of which I'm sure will come up in my blog.  Happy reading!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-05-03 00:06:34</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-05-03 04:06:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>hello-world</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>About</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?page_id=2</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 04:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?page_id=2</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I'm a web developer living in Charlotte, NC with my husband and adorable little boy. We left the glorious city of San Francisco to make our own way in the world. I'm a former Google project manager that now works for herself (woo!). My mantra is "Spread good ideas".]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-05-03 00:06:34</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-05-03 04:06:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>about</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>Location</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Charlotte, NC]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>&quot;They&#039;re just so...cold&quot;</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=10</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 05:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=10</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Atlas Shrugged is my favorite novel.  I'm re-reading it now, and had the opportunity to talk about it very briefly with some of the members of my book club.  A couple of women mentioned that they thought the characters were very cold and they wished they could see more emotion from them.  At the time, I explained that these characters represent an ideal, and not flesh and blood people.  Ayn Rand writes in a Romantic style, so if you want Naturalism, her novels are not the place to look for it.  However, when I thought more about this later, I realized that there's another aspect of the novel that I neglected to mention.  These characters aren't <em>unemotional</em>.  They're just not emotional about the things that most people are emotional about.  For instance, what other people think of you, whether or not you'll find love, or how to go about pursuing your dreams.  I realized that this is what I love so much about these characters.  They know what they want and how to get it.  They have pride in themselves and don't need the approval of others.  Romantic love feeds their souls like any other person, but finding a soulmate is not their primary purpose in life.

Dagny Taggert feels elation and joy at the grandeur of her coming out ball, but utter disappointment when none of the young men attending live up to it's beauty.  She rages at her brother Jim when she realizes that he's using her to save his own hide while also stabbing her in the back.  Hank Rearden knows exactly what to do at his factories, when he's pursuing his goals of making one of the best metals in the world.  But in his home, surrounded by his sneering wife, his ungrateful mother, and his purposeless brother, he is tortured when he doesn't even know how to speak to them and tethered by a sense of duty to take care of them.  When Hank and Dagny meet Ellis Wyatt after the success of the John Galt Line, they are all thrilled to be surrounded by true peers and individuals of strength for one fleeting moment.  All such beautiful and heartbreaking scenes.  How could you say these are cold people?]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-07-10 01:33:21</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-07-10 05:33:21</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>theyre-just-socold</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>8</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[faye]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>amerasu@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.fayecheadle.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>216.239.45.4</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-07-10 16:26:58</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-07-10 20:26:58</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Ah, yes!  I remember that part now that you mention it.  Which is why I'm re-reading the book :)]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>2</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>7</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Richard]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>RichardGleaves@aol.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>72.229.237.136</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-07-10 07:37:14</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-07-10 11:37:14</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[The answer is in the text itself- in the scene between Cheryl Taggart and Dagny:


I was afraid to speak to you. I wanted to ask your forgiveness long ago . . . ever since I learned the truth, I went as far as the door of your office, but I stopped and stood there in the hall and didn't have the courage to go in. . . . I didn't intend to come here tonight. I went out only to . . . to think something over, and then, suddenly, I knew that I wanted to see you, that in the whole of the city this was the only place for me to go and the only thing still left for me to do."

"I'm glad you did."

"You know, Miss Tag—Dagny," she said softly, in wonder, "you're not as I expected you to be at all. . . . They, Jim and his friends, they said you were hard and cold and unfeeling."

"But it's true, Cherryl. I am, in the sense they mean—only have they ever told you in just what sense they mean it?"

"No. They never do. They only sneer at me when I ask them what they mean by anything . . . about anything. What did they mean about you?"

"Whenever anyone accuses some person of being 'unfeeling,' he means that that person is just. He means that that person has no causeless emotions and will not grant him a feeling which he does not deserve. He means that 'to feel' is to go against reason, against moral values, against reality. He means . . . What's the matter?" she asked, seeing the abnormal intensity of the girl's face.

"It's . . . it's something I've tried so hard to understand . . . for such a long time. . . ."

"Well, observe that you never hear that accusation in defense of innocence, but always in defense of guilt. You never hear it said by a good person about those who fail to do him justice. But you always hear it said by a rotter about those who treat him as a rotter, those who don't feel any sympathy for the evil he's committed or for the pain he suffers as a consequence. Well, it's true—that is what I do not feel. But those who feel it, feel nothing for any quality of human greatness, for any person or action that deserves admiration, approval, esteem. These are the things I feel. You'll find that it's one or the other. Those who grant sympathy to guilt, grant none to innocence. Ask yourself which, of the two, are the unfeeling persons. And then you'll see what motive is the opposite of charity."

"What?" she whispered.

"Justice, Cherryl."]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Value of Men</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=16</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 17:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=16</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I saw this article on BBC News the other day, about the development of sperm from stem cells, and the response of certain bloggers:

http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/uk_news/magazine/8142104.stm

<em>"Yet I feel compelled - and not just as the mother of two small boys - to make a spirited defence of the weaker sex. Where would I be without my husband to read 80 pages of a car manual, in French, to find out how the back windscreen-wiper works?"</em>

<em>"Women have always known that men are a bit of a waste of space … Now British scientists have proved how unnecessary blokes truly are by creating the first human sperm from stem cells."</em>

Sure, these are sarcastic comments, but you hear this sort of thing often.  That all men are pigs for instance.  The problem that I see is that men aren't held up to any standard anymore.  It's (apparently) prissy to look nice, to clean up, to be kind to and revere your wife (or partner).  Men are redundant and unnecessary, and mothers are telling their sons that what they're good for is looking up how to fix a windshield wiper (!).

When you say all men are pigs or slobs, they have no reason to act any better than a lazy bum.   When you proliferate throughout the culture the idea that men are useless, why would they strive for greatness?

My husband is a good man who showed me how to have pride in myself.  My father and brother are intelligent and productive men, who both taught me the values I still hold today.  My father-in-law and brother-in-law are both kind and caring and welcomed me into their family, which I'm grateful for.  I'm friends with men that are doting fathers, dedicated husbands, who dress nicely, clean up the dishes, paint works of art, fight for justice, and certainly are no sissies.  They all add so much value to the world, and it would feel like a lesser place without them around.  If you don't see what I see, maybe the solution is to start looking in the right places, instead of slandering the whole sex.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>16</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-07-14 13:57:34</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-07-14 17:57:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-value-of-men</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_oembed_54ff4dac77819b72f2d7501d0484671a</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_oembed_cd31fec89ce902ed94f9401e0001df4f</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Happy Weekends</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=23</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 18:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=23</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I had a really good weekend!  On Friday night, Tim and I just relaxed with some pizza and watched Terminator 2.  It was his birthday, and usually we'd have a nice dinner somewhere, but he just wanted to chill out.  The next day I cleaned up a bit in the morning and then helped out to shoot <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Lyman and Marcela</span>, a short film that I'm working on.  I just did sound, so I basically held the boom mic up from 2-6pm.  It was pretty interesting though.  I haven't worked on films before, so I got to see what it was like.  Lots of waiting :p  What was cool was seeing the film come together after reading the script.  Seeing the characters in front of you interacting can improve the words on the page.  You also have to plan quite a bit.  The director already had storyboards and everything, but we still had to work things out, like keeping the boom mic out of the shot.  The cinematographer and director also argued a bit over "the <a title="180 degree rule" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/180_degree_rule" target="_blank">line</a>".  And finally, it took 4-5 hours to shoot about 3 minutes of dialogue.  Something I'll keep in mind as I continue my filmmaking exploration.  After this experience, I set a goal for myself to write a script for the next <a title="Scary Cow" href="http://www.scarycow.com" target="_blank">Scary Cow</a> round, so I can try out being on the creative end of things.

After I finished the shoot, Tim and I went out for a belated birthday dinner.  He had special ordered a chocolate pie from Mission Beach Cafe, so we went there.  I had this awesome eggplant and cheese raviolis.  The cheese was Red Hawk triple cream from Cowgirl Creamery, a local cheese maker.  So good!  It was a very creamy, but somewhat tangy, cheese.  Then we took home the chocolate pie and I also got a slice of Key Lime Velvet Cream pie to go.  Oh boy.  If you love lime or citrus, this is definitely the pie for you.  I've also had the Lemon Velvet Cream pie which is also really good.  After dinner, we relaxed some more, and had a pretty lazy Sunday.

It was just such a nice weekend!  I remember thinking many times how happy I felt.  I had such a grateful feeling the whole weekend.  Grateful for my husband and grateful for the choices that I've made.  Here's to cherishing life!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>23</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-07-27 14:22:52</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-07-27 18:22:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>happy-weekends</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Homework</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=32</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 03:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=32</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I used to hate doing homework when I was in school.  There were always more fun things to do like play Monkey Island or read really long ubernerd fantasy books late into the night.  And yes, I also did the "but I want to hang out with my boyfriend" thing in college.  Don't look at me that way...he's nice to hang out with.  I married him after all!  Anyways, I have homework again, and it's been hard to break my procrastination habits, but I don't have the anxiety and loathing for it that I used to.  Probably because I'm doing something I actually like this time (more on the "Faye Decides To Be a CS Major" problems later).

What kind of homework do I have?  Well, the first assignment is from <a title="Toastmasters" href="http://toastmasters.org" target="_blank">Toastmasters</a>.  I joined to become a better public speaker and improve my communications skills in general.  The reason being that I needed to practice this whole... talking thing.  Being shy, that was something that I always had a problem with.  There was even a moment in high school when I realized I was so awkward at verbally communicating that I just decided to talk less.  Good one, Faye :p

There's a Toastmasters club at work, and they meet at lunchtime once a week, so it's quite convenient.  It seems like a bit of a cheesy corporate thing to do, but the club I'm in is full of really fun people.  I liked the meetings, so I joined up a few weeks ago and now have to write my Icebreaker speech.  I'll basically do what so many people love to do, and talk about myself.  The speech I have to come up with is to introduce myself to the rest of the club and to get me started down the road of practicing public speaking.

I've also been taking a fiction writing class.  It's through The Writing Salon, a small writing school housed in a San Francisco loft.  I've taken classes with them before and really liked it.  I started these to get into the habit of writing more (that's what this blog is for too) and to hone my wordsmithing skills.  I haven't written very much since high school, so I thought this would be a good way to get back into it, and it's been worth it so far.  Most classes have you free write every week, so it's definitely a good workout for the right side of your brain.  My writing habits aren't the best yet, but I feel like those are getting better as well.

The homework I have for this class is to eavesdrop on other people's conversations, and try to figure out when they're lying.  Someone is actually telling me to snoop on what other people are talking about!  The trouble is, I think I'm around too many honest people, because I haven't been able to pick out any lies yet.  I guess I'll just have to keep listening.

So I actually have homework that I want to do now.  The problem I had so often when I was in school was that I didn't see the point.  Everything is given to you as something you're just "supposed" to know, but the reasons why it's important for your life are so vague.  Integrals are important because you can build bridges or...something.  History is important so we don't repeat bad mistakes...and stuff.  This book is really important to read because people have been reading it for a long time.  Never anything like, it's important for you to read this book as an inspiration for how to live your life or, you need to know about this period of time so that you can relate it to the principles of good and evil and human survival, later using this analysis to judge and be involved in current events.

So, to wrap up this somewhat rambling post, why are writing and speaking important to me right now?  I want to learn how to be a filmmaker, and so far I think that I may want to be a screenwriter or director.  The connection from screenwriter to writing classes is pretty easy.  But what about public speaking?  Well, if I want to be a filmmaker, I'll have to be able to communicate my ideas, not only on paper, but amongst other people.  And possibly (if I'm successful enough), amongst many, many other people.  So Toastmasters seemed like a good place to start.

It's funny that when you realize you're in control of your own life and you know where you want to go, you start to make up your own assignments.  Attend writing classes and finish all assignments given.  Attend Toastmasters meetings and complete speeches in the Competent Communication booklet.  Sign up for Scary Cow and pick 2-3 films to work on in order to get experience on the set.  All of a sudden homework isn't just drudgery being forced on you for arbitrary reasons, it's how you become one of those exciting, fleshed out human beings.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>32</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-08-02 23:34:10</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-08-03 03:34:10</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>homework</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>12</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Mary]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>mary.claire.walker@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>75.176.75.133</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-08-06 12:53:37</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-08-06 16:53:37</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Faye, thanks for sharing your blog. It's nice to see what you've been up to recently - you've been keeping quite busy! I can really relate to this post. "...I needed to practice this whole… talking thing." That sounds exactly like something I'd say. I've struggled with the whole verbal communication thing too and is something I need to work on. Toastmasters sounds like a great idea. Good for you and good luck with it!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>14</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[faye]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>amerasu@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://www.fayecheadle.com</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>216.239.45.4</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-08-07 16:22:31</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-08-07 20:22:31</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi Mary!  Thanks so much :)  I gave my first speech yesterday, and it went pretty well.  It was videotaped, so I'll get to look at it later, which is nice.  The people in our group are really nice, and it's been a fun experience so far.  I hope that you and Mike are having fun with Killian!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>12</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>2</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Boot Camp</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=41</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 20:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=41</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I've been going to a Boot Camp twice a week for a few weeks, and I finally feel like I'm progressing.  I haven't lost any weight yet, but I feel like I'm getting stronger.  Today was the first day I was able to run up the hills we work out on without totally dying.  It was definitely hard, but I felt like I could handle it, whereas before, I had to stop and catch my breath.  I can also do more pushups.  Hooray!  The beginnings of arm strength!

When I've exercised like this in the past, it's always taken a while for me to see results, so I'm hoping that now my weight will start going down :)  Especially since I've been waking up at 5:30am twice a week for the past month or so!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>41</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-08-03 16:47:06</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-08-03 20:47:06</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>boot-camp</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>What&#039;s Up with Faye?</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=45</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 21:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=45</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Since I haven't updated my blog in about a month, here's what's been happening for the past few weeks:
<ol>
	<li>I finished my fiction writing class.  It was fun!  Some of the class members are trying to get a writing group started, so we'll see how that goes.</li>
	<li>Helped shoot for a couple of films.</li>
	<li>Decided I like writing better than filmmaking.  More on that later.</li>
	<li>Found out my dad wants to write a memoir.  Neat!  He has some really good stories about being a Chinese refuge in WWII and immigrating to the US.  Apparently he wanted to be a writer when he was young.  I guess now I know where I got my storytelling bug from :)</li>
	<li>Got sick.  Boo!</li>
	<li>Work...oooo...fun!</li>
</ol>
To expand on #3, I've decided that I don't like working on a film set.  Granted, I've only tried it a few times with amateurs (both experienced and inexperienced), but I found it boring.  I didn't feel any spark for it whatsoever.  The people were usually nice, and now at least I've tried it, so I don't feel like it was a waste.  I was hoping that if I did something like directing or cinematography, I would be more excited.  However, that's a really small part of the film.

Most of the time on the set was setting up a shot and moving the camera around.  So there's a lot of waiting...and some more waiting...and then you do a scene for about a minute.  And then you do the scene again.  And again.  And then you set up the next shot.  This is alright if you get to wait around in a nice comfy chair and read.  But you're mostly standing around all day.  Add in some cold and wind, and you have a pretty miserable day.  A pretty miserable day of waiting around.

Part of the reason I thought I'd like making movies is because it's collaborative.  But that can be good and bad.  They make it look pretty cool on all the behind the scenes features on DVDs.  You see Akira Kurosawa hanging out with his friends, having tea, talking about the film they're writing and just having a grand ol' time.  That's if you're buddies with everyone.  What if you don't gel with the crew?  What if they're not as excited as you are?  It's awkward.  You don't have this wonderful, inspired feeling that comes from collaborating with other creative people, all while combining each of your best assets to create a work of art.  It just falls flat.  You're trying to inspire a bunch of people who are bored or have motives other than creating art.

*sigh*

I could keep trying at this, but that's what I did in college.  I liked something just fine, but I didn't love it, and after "giving it one more shot" for 4 years, I hated it.  I was depressed and full of self-doubt.  What I <em>do</em> like is writing.  When I was in my writing classes, I was excited.   I had fun.  I liked thinking of stories.  So I'm going to focus on that.  Maybe I'll come back to film at some point and maybe I won't.  You have to follow what excites you and cut out the cruft.  And right now film is cruft for me.  I still love <em>watching</em> movies though, so look out for some film reviews soon :)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>45</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-08-28 17:07:59</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-08-28 21:07:59</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>whats-up-with-faye</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>17</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Mary]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email>mary.claire.walker@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url></wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>75.176.75.133</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2009-09-03 19:22:52</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2009-09-03 23:22:52</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[So that's what's been up with Faye! Well, congratulations on figuring out that film might not be your true passion and discovering how much you like writing. It's true, if you had never pursued it, you would have spent your life wondering "what if..."  Somewhat on a similar note, I recently discovered being self-employed, not in a traditional 9-5) isn't as glamorous as I thought it would be! But trying out something else definitely made me appreciate the steady paycheck and other comforts of the 9-5. And now I no longer wonder so much what it would be like!  :)

Your dad should totally write a memoir! You should help him or encourage him on that!]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Insidiousness of What Other People Think</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=56</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2009 16:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=56</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I don't remember how I found this, but it's a good article:

<a href="http://www.happinessinthisworld.com/2009/05/24/the-good-guy-contract/">The Good Guy Contract
</a>

Here's how the author defines it:
<blockquote>The Good Guy Contract was simple:  I would agree to be nice to you, to advise you, to sacrifice for you, to care about you—and in return you would agree to believe that I was wise, compassionate, excellent as a human being in every way, and finally and most importantly, <em>you would like me</em>.</blockquote>
It's common in the  present culture to believe that altruism is a noble philosophy.  But what does it really mean?  That sacrificing yourself for others is moral and good.  Your entire morality and self-esteem (for how can you feel good about yourself without knowing that you're moral?) is built upon other people.  I hear a lot of lip service paid to "doing something for yourself" so that you don't go crazy, but more often, when you see a person or their actions held up on a pedestal, it's because of their sacrifice.

You might go through life thinking that you're doing things to make yourself happy, but I see so many people hung up and anxious about <em>what other people think</em>.  I have this problem myself.  It's pretty easy to figure out what you want, and if no one else is around, it's trivial to do exactly what you want to.  But it's so rare that other people aren't involved.  Ay, there's the rub.  All of a sudden, there are these other pressures involved.  Well, I want to stay home and relax tonight, but I don't want to disappoint so-and-so because of whatnot.  Then the anxiety comes.  I <em>want</em> to do something, but I <em>don't want</em> to feel that someone is displeased with me.  Well, should you be making decisions because of what you want or because of what you don't want?  That's what I try to keep in mind.  The author is right, it does take practice.  You just have to bite the bullet and risk finding out that someone doesn't like what you're doing.  Most of the time it's not so bad, and when you survive another's disappointment one time, you gain more confidence for the next time.

So why are the opinions of others so insidious?  Because it feels so good to get praise.   However, praise is fleeting, and you can't bring up old praise in your mind to make yourself feel better down the road.  You have to learn to feel good because of your accomplishments, otherwise you're left constantly needing a praise fix.  You'll surround yourself with people you don't care about because they happen to be there.  Your relationships are built, not on values, but on whether or not the other person can give you your fix.  When your self-esteem comes from inside yourself, you can feel happy without anyone else around.  If you feel down, it's easy to think of all of the good things that you've done.  Life seems so simple once you realize this and live your life for yourself.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>56</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-08-29 12:52:54</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-08-29 16:52:54</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-insidiousness-of-what-other-people-think</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Hierarchy in Education</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=65</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=65</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>65</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-09-14 20:35:55</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Priceless</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=67</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=67</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Hooray for Netflix Instant and the Roku!  They enable Tim and I watch lots of movies.  A recent one that I liked was <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Priceless</span> with Audrey Tatou and Gad Elmaleh (or <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Hors de Prix</span> if you're French).  My only complaint would be that it's about a gold digger and a gigolo, which is not the most respectable employment, but they are a charming and endearing pair.  Just look at them:

Ok, so....Audrey Tatou just looks kind of drunk.  Actually, she <em>is</em> drunk.  But never you mind; trust me, she gets charming.  The gist of the movie is that Jean, played by Gad Elmaleh (he's Moroccan, the Wikipedia told me so), is a concierge at a fancy hotel in the Riviera.  He's manning the bar one night by sleeping on the couch (more with the trust, I don't want to spoil things too much), when Miss Terribly Sexy Irene, played by Audrey Tatou, walks in and mistakes him for another patron of said fancy hotel.  He plays along for a while and ends up sleeping with Miss Terribly Drunk Terribly Sexy Irene.  Much to her embarassment in the morning, he is not the wealthy man she thought he was, but a lowly dog walker and waiter.  This puts her in a spot of trouble as she is the mistress of a man that's actually loaded.  He doesn't appreciate the gold digger messing around on him, so he kicks her to the curb.  So now Irene is really miffed with Jean and wants nothing to do with her and poor Jean is smitten.  The only way for him to impress her now is to become a gigolo.

It's a sweet and funny romance set on the Cote D'Azur, so it also has gorgeous scenery.

What I liked
<ul>
	<li>Beautiful actors - Gad Elmaleh surprised me.  He doesn't really pop out as you as a handsome man when you first see him.  He certainly wasn't bad looking, I just didn't think, "Oh, <em>that's</em> a handsome man".  The kind of reaction you have when you look at someone like, say, Jon Hamm.  The man: &lt;pic&gt; The reaction: dang.  It wasn't until</li>
	<li>Beautiful scenery</li>
	<li>funny!  but benevolent</li>
	<li>romantic</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>67</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-03-30 17:55:03</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Spiders are rad...</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=73</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 21:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=73</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.amnh.org/exhibitions/spidersilk/?src=e_h"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-76" title="detailed_rm" src="http://www.fayecheadle.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/detailed_rm.jpg" alt="detailed_rm" width="652" height="433" /></a>

<a href="http://www.amnh.org/exhibitions/spidersilk/?src=e_h">This</a> is incredible.  And those spiders are awesome.  I love the gold color of the tapestry!  <a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=113223398">Here's</a> a link to the NPR story.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>73</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-10-02 17:58:16</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-10-02 21:58:16</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>spiders-are-rad</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Autumn Festival</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=75</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=75</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>75</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-10-02 19:56:13</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>detailed_rm</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?attachment_id=76</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2009 06:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/detailed_rm.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>76</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2009-10-03 02:17:25</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2009-10-03 06:17:25</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>detailed_rm</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>73</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url>http://www.fayecheadle.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/detailed_rm.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_attached_file</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2009/10/detailed_rm.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_metadata</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:6:{s:5:"width";s:3:"800";s:6:"height";s:3:"533";s:14:"hwstring_small";s:23:"height='85' width='128'";s:4:"file";s:23:"2009/10/detailed_rm.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:2:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:3:{s:4:"file";s:23:"detailed_rm-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";s:3:"150";s:6:"height";s:3:"150";}s:6:"medium";a:3:{s:4:"file";s:23:"detailed_rm-300x199.jpg";s:5:"width";s:3:"300";s:6:"height";s:3:"199";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:10:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Vegetarian Myth</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=80</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 20:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=80</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Hi Everyone!  Here's a little review of a book I finished recently.  It's adapted from a short speech I made in Toastmasters:

After 20 years as a vegan, author Lierre Keith sat at her kitchen table, distraught.  Her health was in shambles, and she had just been told by her doctor that needs to eat meat again to heal.  It was an emotional experience for her, but she was at the end of her rope.  She had caved in and bought a can of tuna fish.  Ms. Keith describes this scene herself in her book, The Vegetarian Myth.
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">
<blockquote><em>I sat at my kitchen table with a plastic fork.  I didn't use my silverware or my dishes.  I opened the can.  How could I actually do this?  I broke it down into the tiniest steps.  Pick up the fork. Put the fork in the tuna. I was so desperate.  Pain was the inhabitant of my body, and I was only the shadow it cast.  Lift the fork toward you. I had come to the end.  Open your mouth. And I was so, so tired.</em></blockquote>
</div>
<blockquote>
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">

<em>I ate it.</em>

</div>
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">

<em>I don't know how to describe what happened next.  "I felt like I was coming out of a coma," one ex-vegan told me.  "It was like being plugged into a low-voltage battery," another friend said.  I could feel every cell in my body -- literally, every cell -- pulsing. And finally, finally being fed.</em>

</div>
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">

<em>Oh, god, I thought: this is what if feels like to be alive.</em>

</div></blockquote>
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">
<blockquote><em>I put my head down and sobbed.</em></blockquote>
</div>
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">

<em><span style="font-style: normal;">Ms. Keith's journey started at 16, when she decided to become a vegan.  She grew up in the 60s and 70s, looking up to environmentalist icons like Iron Eyes Cody and Rachel Carson</span>.</em> She had rejected the factory farming model for it's inhumane treatment of animals and the harm it does to the environment.  However, after twenty years with episodes of low blood sugar, an absent menstrual period, and debilitating back problems, her deteriorating health was one of the main reasons she began to question whether or not it was right for her to be a vegan.  In addition, the difficulties of raising her own garden without the use of animal products led her to see the real consequences of her choices.

</div>
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">

The most important elements for healthy soil are Nitrogen, Phosphorus, and Potassium.  You can get all of these things contained in a simple bag of fertilizer.  Simple, that is, unless you're a vegan.  Lierre Keith read the label on her fertilizer.  There she saw two important ingredients: blood meal and bone meal.  A traditional source for Nitrogen is blood meal or manure, but using these would violate Ms. Keith's vegan ethics.  She could get nitrogen synthetically, but the fossil fuels needed to produce it would thwart her desire to be ecologically sustainable.  Phosphorus is another problem.  The traditional source of phosphorus?  Bone meal.  The non-animal source?  Sedimentary rock.  But again, this non-animal source has to be mined and transported, which isn't exactly a green solution.  Finally, to enrich the earth with Potassium you can use wood ash or cover crops, which are both sustainable and from non-animal sources, but this is a moot point without the other two elements of this important trio.

</div>
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">

And then there were the slugs.  They would destroy her garden and eat everything that she tried to plant.  She couldn't use pesticides, again, because of her moral and ecological views.  Her first solution was something called diatomaceous earth.  It's organic, so at first glance it seems ok.  However, then Ms. Keith found out how it worked.  It kills soft bellied slugs by cutting them repeatedly, after which they die from dehydration.  So that was out.  There were also copper barriers, but that was much too expensive.  Next, the author tried to pick them off herself and release them to the woods, but she was faced with yet another problem.  The whole reason they were in her garden was because that's where the food was.  If she put them in the woods, she wouldn't have to see it, but they would die there too.  The solution she stuck with was this: ducks and chickens.  The chickens she brought in ate anything that moved, including the slugs.  Her duck, whom she named Miracle...well, this is how she described what happened, "One bite of bug and she exploded into quacks of joy: this is what I was born for!  The slugs were history."

</div>
<div style="margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px;">

This was the beginning of Ms. Keith's moral conundrum.  Every life form on this earth evolved in a relationship with other forms of life.  There are predators and prey, grazers and the plants that they graze.  What do animals eat?  Either other animals or plants, or a combination of both.  And what do plants eat?  They don't just get their energy from the sun, they get their energy from us.  Plants essentially eat animals.  And this is what Ms. Keith learned from her garden.  The food chain is not a line, but a cycle.  To put it very simply, an animal eats a plant, it gets eaten by another animal or dies on it's own, it decomposes and the plants use this material to nourish themselves and grow, and the cycle starts all over again.  The author had accepted a way of life where she didn't believe that death was necessary to eat.  However, in growing her garden, she discovered that she had been flouting the cycle of life, and of nature, for years.  In order to grow her food, she realized that it begged for the blood of animals.  In order to save her lettuce from slugs, she had to either kill them herself or have her ducks and chickens root them out and do the killing for her.  Every plant and animal has it's place in nature, and by industrializing our food supply, we've removed ourselves so far from this that we have to relearn where each of these plants and animals should go.  This isn't just something that meat eaters have to examine, it's something that vegans and vegetarians must keep in mind as well.

Ms. Keith's book is split up into three sections, "Moral Vegetarians", "Political Vegetarians", and "Nutritional Vegetarians".  The stories I've related above are part of her exploration of the moral reasons to be vegetarian in the first part of her book.  In the sections exploring the political and nutritional reasons for cutting meat out of your diet, she challenges the notions that it's both environmentally sustainable to eat a vegetarian diet and the fact that it will improve your health.

</div>
Do I think it's impossible to thrive and live on a vegan diet?  I'm not completely convinced of that yet, but I thought this book brought up questions that both vegans and non-vegans should consider.  Questions like, how does an annual crop - like wheat, soybeans, or corn - affect the earth differently than a perennial  - like grass, berries bushes, and trees?  What are the environmental effects of having an industrialized agriculture and farmers only planting one or two crops repeatedly?  How does eating soy affect your body?  What are the nutritional effects of removing animal products from your diet?  This is a fascinating book, and I've only told you a portion of it.

As a former vegan herself, Ms. Keith approaches the subject matter with brutal honesty, but also compassion.  I admired this greatly even when I didn't agree with her politics and values, and she definitely lets you know what these are. This is someone who dedicated herself to a way of life and an ideology that she found crumbling before her eyes.  She could have turned away and ignored the questions that kept coming up in her mind, but instead she bravely faced each one.  We should all use her example to be a little more brave and learn about where our food comes from.

More reviews of this book (some detailing more on the political and nutritional parts of the book):
<a href="http://www.proteinpower.com/drmike/lipid-hypothesis/the-vegetarian-myth/">Review by Dr. Michael Eades</a>
<a href="http://freetheanimal.com/2009/10/the-vegetarian-myth-revisited.html">Review at Free the Animal (links to his 4 other mini-reviews as well)</a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>80</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-02-14 16:50:05</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-02-14 20:50:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-vegetarian-myth</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Ann Druyan and the Separation of the Mind and the Spirit</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=91</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 21:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=91</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Ann Druyan cowrote the <em>Cosmos</em> television series with Carl Sagan, and was his wife for the last 15 years of his life.  I don't recall how I came across this speech, but it's great.  It's a talk she gave to the Committee for Skeptical Inquiry.  She describes the prevalent schism between material reality and the spiritual just beautifully.  <a href="http://www.csicop.org/si/show/ann_druyan_talks_about_science_religion/">Have a look!</a>
<blockquote>
<p style="margin-top: 1em; margin-right: 0.6em; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 0.6em; padding: 0px;">What happened four or five hundred years ago? During this period there was a great bifurcation. We made a kind of settlement with ourselves. We said, okay, so much of what we believed and what our parents and our ancestors taught us has been rendered untenable. The Bible says that the Earth is flat. The Bible says that we were created separately from the rest of life. If you look at it honestly, you have to give up these basic ideas, you have to admit that the Bible is not infallible, it’s not the gospel truth of the creator of the universe. So what did we do? We made a corrupt treaty that resulted in a troubled peace: We built a wall inside ourselves.</p>
<p style="margin-top: 1em; margin-right: 0.6em; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 0.6em; padding: 0px;">It made us sick. In our souls we cherished a myth that was rootless in nature. What we actually knew of nature we compartmentalized into a place that could not touch our souls. The churches agreed to stop torturing and murdering scientists. The scientists pretended that knowledge of the universe has no spiritual implications.</p>
<p style="margin-top: 1em; margin-right: 0.6em; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 0.6em; padding: 0px;">It’s a catastrophic tragedy that science ceded the spiritual uplift of its central revelations: the vastness of the universe, the immensity of time, the relatedness of all life and it’s preciousness on this tiny world.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>91</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-02-27 17:09:00</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-02-27 21:09:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>ann-druyan-and-the-separation-of-the-mind-and-the-spirit</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Next Chernobyl?</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=117</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=117</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704893604576198421680697248.html
http://www.latimes.com/news/opinion/commentary/la-oe-goldberg-japan-20110315,0,5406257.column
http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/03/14/fukushiima_analysis/
http://www.snopes.com/photos/technology/fallout.asp]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>117</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-03-15 15:36:31</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Inconvenient Environmentalist</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=167</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=167</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[This is an interesting video from The Nature Convervancy's chief scientist, Peter Kareiva.

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4BOEQkvCook" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

I don't agree with all of it, but it's refreshing to see environmentalism from a man-based standpoint. He also fights against some myths that really bother me, romanticizing nature without man in it and technology against nature, to name a couple.

What he views as a tactical problem, though, I see as a philosophical one. He starts to make the point that it's about value, and I agree. But how do you know what to value? What guidelines to you use to judge your values? How do you deal with the fact that other people may value different things? This is where, personally, the Objectivist definition of value has been helping me think about this.
<blockquote>Value” is that which one acts to gain and keep, “virtue” is the action by which one gains and keeps it. “Value” presupposes an answer to the question: of value to whom and for what? “Value” presupposes a standard, a purpose and the necessity of action in the face of an alternative. Where there are no alternatives, no values are possible.</blockquote>
You need your mind for this and if you want others to follow, you need their minds as well. You don't persuade people with legislature. You don't organize strong and lasting communities by bashing people or companies.

Community arises from *value* and what people do to gain or keep a value.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>167</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-10-17 13:21:27</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Women&#039;s Studies</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=170</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=170</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[When I was in college, I had a very dim view of the feminism. I was lucky to have grown up surrounded by strong women and men. My mom, dad, and older brother were always encouraging my sister and I in math and science. They knew that young women were not always told they could cut it in these classes and made sure that we had positive reinforcement at home. Both of us were pressed to take the most advanced math and science classes that we could. My brother really encouraged me to learn about computers and programming. We were told through words and through actions that our intelligence was valued. We were told that we were beautiful, inside and out.

I had never felt oppressed because of my gender, so I didn't think feminism was important to me. It seemed like it was important in the past because it allowed women to take on roles other than housewife and mother, but now it wasn't necessary anymore. The battle seemed fought and won. I felt ambivalent about it. I carried this with me as I started going to college as a Computer Science major.

College was really difficult for me. Computer Science is a difficult major in and of itself, but I also struggled with tremendous self doubt. I may have been encouraged in more intellectual endeavors, but I was petrified of being seen as stupid. This is something I've struggled with for a long time and things got really bad for me once I was in college. The difficult academic workload and the general turmoil that a young person of that age goes through were enough to completely buckle my self confidence.

During my sophomore year, my roommate was a Women's Studies major. We got along pretty well at the beginning of the year, but by the end of the year, there was a lot of enmity between us. We had drastically diverged as far as our political beliefs and my ambivalence towards feminism had turned into bitterness. I couldn't see what the point was. I saw she and her classmates talking about encouraging women in engineering, but I also saw that none of them wanted to join me there. And it wasn't until years later that I realized how much this hurt me and how much that feeling of isolation had affected me.

One thing that I remember thinking during this time was, "Here I am, toughing it out through all these difficult courses, and she's talking about empowering women as a glorified English major!"

What is feminism?

The most important part of feminism, in my mind, is having empathy for other people. It's about treating others with respect and trying to understand that they might have things to deal with that you don't. You should do this with all people, but feminism focuses on the struggles that women have. I think it's necessary to have a word specifically for female struggle because it helps us organize our thoughts. That's what words and concepts are for. Concepts allow us to focus on certain perceptions so that we can discuss them with others or try to better understand them ourselves.

This is what happened to me in college. I didn't have empathy for my roommate and she didn't have empathy for me.

What is oppression?
Oppression is prolonged cruel or unjust treatment or control. What has happened with the word "feminism" is that we created it to start talking about how women are oppressed. The conversation went from votes for women to marriage to women in the workplace to having control over our bodies. We talked about rape and equal opportunities and gender roles. And the word feminism has been associated to all of these discussions. Anytime you hear someone call themselves a feminist, you add a new perception to what the concept means to you. It could be someone that sounds reasonable to you, so therefore, feminism sounds reasonable. Or it could be someone horrible, so now you think that feminism is horrible. Or it could be a mix of both. This is why we have people proclaiming they're feminists and some people proclaiming that they don't need this word.

women against feminism: https://twitter.com/WomAgainstFem/status/500744294714462208/photo/1]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>170</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-03-22 19:15:10</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>So Good They Can&#039;t Ignore You</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=175</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=175</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[How to be happy in your career is one of the biggest questions that people ask themselves. You usually hear the advice of "follow your dreams" and "do what you love". I used to agree with this. Recently, however, I have not only questioned it but grown to dislike it quite a bit. The biggest influence in my thinking here would be the show Dirty Jobs. 

At first glance you might think this show is made for shock value and to gross people out with how dirty the jobs can be. Some examples of the jobs seen on this show are worm dung farmer and avian vomitologist. Sounds lovely, right? 

I loved this book. It encapsulated a lot of things I had already been thinking about, like the misguided advice to "follow your passion", and also gave some new perspectives on how to be happy in your work. 


The advice to “follow your passion” is not only incomplete, but dangerous.
Cultivating a skill will make you more happy than chasing a dream. It can also end up being your dream when you didn’t realize it.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>175</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2014-11-18 13:13:05</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Beginners</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=100</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 03:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=100</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/focus_features/beginners/">Beginners</a>
<blockquote><strong>A gay Christopher Plummer</strong> : They had some wonderfully loud music in the club tonight! *nnn st nnn st nnn st*  What kinda music's that?
<strong>Ewan McGregor as his son</strong> : It's probably house music...
<strong>Christopher Pummer</strong> : House music...hehe...ok... [writes it down on notepad]</blockquote>
I want to see this movie for that scene and that scene alone.  Plus there's a dog that speaks in subtitles.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>100</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-02-02 23:26:09</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-02-03 03:26:09</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>beginners</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>My Baby Is Forcing Me to Use Technology</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=111</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 22:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=111</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I'm such a luddite, which is funny, because I'm a Computer Science major. It's mostly the influence of my parents. My dad doesn't even have a cell phone. I don't usually stay on top of new technologies, but that's all changing now that I have a baby.

I barely have time (or the free hands) to brush my teeth let alone hop on the computer. However, since I have an iPhone, there's a lot I have at my fingertips now that I never explored before. I didn't <strong>have</strong> to explore, so I just didn't. Now my phone is one of the few links I have to the adult world.

It all started when I'd hop on my iPhone while nursing. I use an application (which I didn't even download myself; Tim did) called Total Baby to keep track of diapers, nursing, and other various baby things. So I started using that. And then I started just reading my e-mail or checking Facebook while occupied with Henry. Because I was nursing so much in the beginning, it was the easiest way for me to do anything, so I started exploring what I could do on my phone. I remembered that there was a Kindle application, so I could read books on it. I could play games on it. I could update my blog on it. I even went and got a Twitter account. Oh my goodness, would you look at that! Technology is useful :p

So, thank you, Henry. Thank you for forcing Mommy to use the interwebs 'n stuff.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>111</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-02-16 18:18:14</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-02-16 22:18:14</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>my-baby-is-forcing-me-to-use-technology</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>iPhone Addiction</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=123</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 11:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=123</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[So...remember when I posted that Henry has forced me to use technology? Or, more accurately, how he was the impetus for me to find new uses for my iPhone? Well, now I'm addicted to the damn thing! Crap.

I do love my "space phone", as someone called it the other day, but I've been reminded recently that you have to be mindful of how you use technology. I think the social applications are the worst. On the one hand, they're fantastic for keeping up with friends and family, finding fascinating news from unexpected places, and in general being connected with people that aren't near you geographically. On the other, it's a time suck! 

How many of those links you follow will genuinely improve your life and mind? Are you staying in touch with your friends or passing idle time? Do you really need to know that your friends in Atlanta are going to happy hour next Tuesday? Oh wait...I do, I might be there...

I thought about all this last night when Tim and I just sat and played with Henry after dinner. We didn't watch TV. We weren't playing Kickin' Momma on our phones or checking our Twitter feed. We all just sat together. Henry was so content. He didn't try to grab at our speakers or pull the books out of the shelves, which is what he normally does if we're with him but not really paying attention. I guess he's been trying to tell us something.

Later that night I thought about all the books I've been meaning to read and how they've been piling up. Blogs and stories I've been meaning to write and haven't gotten to. Tasks that have been languishing on my todo list. Basically, <em>my life</em>. And then I thought about all the levels on Cut the Rope I've beaten.

Watch out for that idle time. Stop and think about how you really want to be using it.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>123</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-08-09 07:55:45</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-08-09 11:55:45</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>iphone-addiction</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Harsh Discipline</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=124</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 18:36:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=124</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I always try to explore why certain ideas resonate with me emotionally. I believe in reason and that it is our only means of knowledge, but emotions are equally important. Emotions are automatic responses to values (thanks, Ayn Rand!). Emotions are ways for our subconscious to take in vast amounts of information and experiences and boil them down into feelings that help us make decisions (thanks, Malcolm Gladwell!).

I read a book called <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Raising Cain: Protecting the Emotional Life of Boys</span> (which is a great book, by the way) and came across the following quote:
<blockquote>Instead of fostering the development of internal controls, harsh discipline reinforces the idea that discipline comes from external forces - from parents, principals, the cops, or the courts. Instead of leading a boy toward better decision making, it prevents him from internalizing the values - and learning the lessons of empathy, respect, and reason - that lead to responsible, moral behavior and emotional accountability. Those lost links weaken the chain of conscience as a boy moves through life.</blockquote>
This passage really moved me and stuck with me. It also got me thinking about how we raise Henry. I've been drawn to a two particular philosophies, namely Montessori and <a href="http://www.positivediscipline.com/what-is-positive-discipline.html">Positive Discipline</a>. Both of these foster the independence of the child. They both are a wonderful principled approach to raising children; very scientific in a certain way. I also think I was drawn to these things because of the cultivation of that internal value system.

I'm constantly cultivating my own values and learning how best to do that. I try to ask myself the following questions: "Does spending time on this pursue a value of mine? What value is this action related to? Does spending time on this take time away from a value that I've been neglecting?". It's really easy to get distracted with TV and social media and other things and these questions help me stay focused.

It took me a while to learn to do this for myself, which is why I want to start early with Henry. It's not just easy to get distracted by technology, it's easy to get distracted by what other people value. Highschool is a great example of this. I remember my days and many of my peers days being filled with the question "Will this look good for college?" versus "Is this pursuing <strong>my</strong> values?". And I've encountered many people who get spit out of the college system, look around, and realize they're lost.

How is this related to discipline? Think about how we normally discipline children. We punish and reward. We reward them when they do things we like and punish or shame them for the things that bother us. It's all based on the values of <strong>the parents</strong> and on other external forces. Positive Discipline is a non-reward and non-punitive philosophy. Montessori is an educational philosophy that focuses on learning the child's will. And both of these move from putting external pressure on children towards giving them a framework to make their own decisions.

Something to think about the next time you deal with your toddler that's hitting and throwing everything in sight!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>124</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-06-13 14:36:29</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-06-13 18:36:29</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>harsh-discipline</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>An Influx of Inspiration</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=160</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 17:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=160</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Tim and I attended <a href="http://www.atlantaobjectivists.com/atloscon-2012/" target="_blank">ATLOSCon</a> a few weeks ago, and ever since then I've been chewing on all of the ideas that I learned about there. I learned things about temperament, style, the fixed mindset versus the growth mindset, and building community.

The first class that really stuck with me was the temperament class. It was all about the ways in which people are different and how to take that into consideration in our relationships. They used Myers-Brigg personality types to help explain this, and the Thinking/Feeling dichotomy was really relevant to where Tim and I disagree the most. The main difference in these types is that the "thinking" type of person prefers to take a step back and judge things from a distance whereas the "feeling" type of person doesn't hesitate to talk about how they're feeling.

Feelings are hard for me, whereas Tim is very comfortable with them. He knows what he feels and why and wants to talk about it right away. I need a little while to even figure out<em> why </em>I'm feeling a certain way and if it's ok to feel that way. Only after that can I approach a conflict or problem solve. I had usually tried to talk about conflicts right away because I thought I would be hiding things if I didn't. This class really encouraged me to recognize when distance was actually better for me. Of course, Tim is still really great at making sure I don't overanalyze :)

The other idea that was new to me was the fixed mindset versus a growth mindset (this comes from the psychologist <a href="http://amzn.com/0345472322" target="_blank">Carol Dweck</a>). A fixed mindset is when you think people are inherently talented or intelligent and can do nothing to change those innate skills. The growth mindset is when you believe you can train yourself in a skill and get better and better.

You can have one of these mindsets overall, or you can have a fixed mindset about certain things and a growth mindset about others. The speaker mentioned that she typically had a growth mindset when it came to learning and found it easy to study even when a subject was difficult to her at first. But she had a fixed mindset when it came to sports. She used to believe that she just wasn't athletic and never attempted to get better in that area. Once she was introduced to the idea of these two mindsets, she could break out of that mold and use the same persistence she had used with her studies in improving her fitness.

There's so much more I want to share from this conference, but I think I'll save them for their own posts. I'm especially excited about how to build a better community. But I'll talk about that later. Oh, the suspense!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>160</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-06-21 13:11:33</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-06-21 17:11:33</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>an-influx-of-inspiration</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Building Bonds</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=162</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 01:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=162</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[With the advent of social networks it can be easy to get caught up in building communities by interacting with people online. It makes it trivial to connect to someone you have lost touch with or to find someone with common interests that you may not have found before we had Facebook or Twitter. But does it really help you bond with people? <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/05/is-facebook-making-us-lonely/8930/">The Atlantic</a> has a really good take on this.

I've been thinking about that in terms of my own attempts at building community in Charlotte and have gotten a lot of good ideas recently from friends and what I read. The three things that have stuck with me are how to use social media effectively, great leaders create other leaders, and being a good leader also means being a good host.

When building a community around a particular value or interest, it's not enough to simply make a connection. You need to reach out personally to people and create a bond. It's just as important to cultivate new connections as it is a keep older ones going. And if you use social networks, interact with people! Don't just click "Like" or "Share" buttons. Write something to your friends. Use all of these wonderful tools we have to meet up with people face to face instead of just sending ideas into the ether.

If you're a leader of a community, it's important to create other leaders in your group. Many local communities come and go with whomever is in charge. In college I was part of a wonderful philosophy club that fizzled as soon as the president left. If you have more than one person creating and managing events then it's less likely that all of those people will leave with no one to fill the void.

A compelling way to create more leaders is to find out about the passions and interests of the other members of your group and have them talk about those. Encourage them to create an event around what they love. It's easy for people to do that. And then give them help in the form of co-hosting an event if that makes them more comfortable. Mentor them into becoming good leaders.

And lastly, learn how to be a good host or hostess. That's something that I work on quite a bit! I tend to get caught up in day to day stress, so much so that I don't think I can handle doing something like making dinner for a friend with a newborn or having a dinner party. But I've done both of these things recently and it was quite rejuvenating. I may have been physically tired from being the hostess, but my soul was filled. I also thought of many things that I could improve on, and instead of making me feel bad I was looking forward to what I could plan next.

The most important part of being a hostess is to enjoy your guests.  Surround yourself with people that you value. Make them feel as comfortable as you can. Be kind. Be generous. This goes for friends as well as members of a club. The reason it's valuable to have community in the first place is to find like-minded people, spread good ideas, and support each other. I try to remember this when I'm feeling the stress of providing for people or managing a social event.

I hope to use all of these ideas to create wonderful communities in Charlotte. I think it's a great city, but it could be stronger. What better way to create strength than by building bonds between the people here?]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>162</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-13 21:45:43</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-14 01:45:43</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>building-bonds</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Sexual Harassment and How to be an Ally</title>
		<link>http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=179</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 15:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>faye</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.fayecheadle.com/?p=179</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I've been thinking a lot about feminism and women in tech recently. HR departments focus their efforts on how to avoid punishment and on documenting bad behavior. What I feel they lack is training employees how to be an ally. When you are an ally, you speak up when you see someone being treated unjustly. You are an ally when you notice that someone is feeling isolated, not just when you are aware of obvious abuse. If you're a manager, you regularly check in with your reports to give them an open space to report problems instead of expecting them to come to you. You are an ally when you encourage a colleague to speak up when they want to let something go.

Do you wonder what you can do to help women succeed in science and technology fields? Do you wonder how to make your office a warm and happy environment? Do you want to put an end to toxic behavior? The answer is to foster relationships. Do what you can to let your co-workers know that you're looking out for them. There are a lot of ways to do this.

The public way to do this is to call out good work that’s being ignored as well as discouraging bad behavior. You can support someone in private by letting them know when you disagree with how they're being treated or by getting them help if they don’t know what to do. Maybe they can’t speak up to their manager, so you go to yours for help. You can let them know when they do good work and let them know of ways to improve when they can do better. Did you notice that they solved a problem in a really interesting way? Tell them. Did you notice that they struggled with something, but got help at the right time or you were impressed with how they persevered? Tell them.

When someone is being sexist or abusive, speak up. It’s not only important for the person being abused, it can be important to anyone that happens to be listening. If it's intimidating to chastise a co-worker in front of a large group, another option is to tell them privately that you're disappointed with their behavior. If this is the route you take, it’s also important to let the abused person know that you support them. A feeling of isolation can be worse than any public shame. Let them know that they aren’t isolated.

There was a long time when I felt alone as a woman in tech and I didn’t even realize it. I suffered for years because of this. It would have really helped me if our sexual harassment training was used as an opportunity to show what it looks like to be a good person instead of dwelling on the salacious details of the bad examples.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>179</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2015-03-10 11:52:48</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2015-03-10 15:52:48</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>sexual-harassment-and-how-to-be-an-ally</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
